#### KARTHIKEYAN. M

karthik.civilproject@gmail.com

9865077060

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

To work with a progressive organization in which I can contribute my technical and **Project Management** skills to enhance my own productivity at the same time achieving the organizational objectives with the attribute of time and quality.

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a qualified Project Manager with **an MBA** and **Civil Engineering** Academic Background and **PMP** having **20+ years**' experience of technical and Project management experience in handling all types of civil projects includes Multi-storey Apartments, Villas Industrial Residential, and Commercial Buildings.

Presently, working as a **Project Manager** in Srivari Property Developers, Coimbatore from August 2012 to till date. I have been carrying out end to end lead in all project proceedings.

# PROJECT MANAGEMENT EXPERTISE

#### **Residential Projects handled**

Multistoried building with 13 floors consists of 154 flats. The project cost: Rs. 100 Crore and Built-up area of a building: 4,50,000 sq. ft. It was awarded as one of India's Top 100 Project for quality construction.

#### **Commercial Projects handled**

A commercial complex with B+G+4 floors with a built-up area of **60,000+Sft**. The complex was entirely a Post-tensioned [**PT Structure**] framed structure.

#### **Industrial Projects handled**

Food processing units, Feed production units, Silos, Iodized salt processing units, and retail outlets.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## SRI VARI PROPERTY DEVELOPERS [P] LTD.

#### **Leading Builders and Infrastructure Developers in Coimbatore**

Designation : Project Manager

Period : August 2012 to till date

#### **Residential Apartment**

- The recently completed project was a residential MSB, which has a Basement, G + 11 Floors.
- The apartment comprises **154 flats** with amenities such as a swimming pool, gym, Theatre, Games room, and Roof Garden.
- My Team won the CRISIL Five-star rating was awarded for this building.
- This project was awarded as Best Finished Concrete Structure in Tamilnadu by Ultra-tech Cement Awards and Indian Concrete Institute.

#### **Commercial complex**

- The commercial complex consists of B+G+4 floors with a built-up area of 60,000+Sft.
- This complex was entirely a Post-tensioned [**PT Structure**] framed structure.
- The entire front facing of the commercial complex was covered with structural glazing.
- Also completed the interiors works for MNC clients as per their specs whose net worth was approx. 20 Crores.

#### Responsibilities

- Project Management Complete project management, including project coordination, construction management, schedule control & payment certification, and all other total activities in Project.
- **Interaction** Coordination with all contractors & chairing a meeting.
- **Design Management** Review of drawings and BOQ with technical specifications, coordinate with Architects, Structural consultant, electrical consultant, swimming pool consultant, MEP, STP, HVAC, and other consultants. Analyze the **GFC** drawings with specifications to determine project requirements and to prepare various estimates for execution.
- Schedule Control Pre-planning, periodically organizing and chairing a meeting,
  planning and scheduling micro-level programs, monitoring, and tracking schedules.
- Construction Management Monitoring all types of construction tasks as per the scheduled work sequence with Quality consciousness.
- **Documentation** Preparing the minutes of meetings, status reports, DPR, WPR, budget tracking system, weekly programs, and fortnight schedule. Verify the documents before issuing the **BOQ** and also the issue of the work order to start the work within the schedule
- **Reviewing** the daily progress reports, monthly project reports, and maintaining documents as per the standard operating procedure.
- Safety –Regular monitoring of the health and safety of workers on the site.

# VKS Exports [P] Limited

#### Leading Export oriented unit involved with Poultry Processing & Exports

Designation : Project Manager

Period : October 2007- July 2012

#### **Industrial Building**

- Poultry meat processing unit with an area of **260000 Sqft** [ Value Rs 120Cr]
- Poultry feed production unit with an area of **37 Acres** [ Value Rs 100Cr]
- Iodized salt production Unit [Value Rs 70Cr]

## Responsibilities

- Handled industry-oriented construction activities
- Managed project management staff and monitored their workload.
- Executed all types of construction activities such as preparation of estimates, taking measurements, contractor's bill certification, etc.,
- Periodic valuations on completed works and assessed contractor's financial claims for payments.
- Managed financial reports which include annual/monthly budget and expenditure
- Prepared work schedule and monitoring the progress of works.
- Regular meetings with the client and client representatives and discussed project progress, etc.

#### **SRE Constructions**

# A Construction Firm undertaking civil Contracts with Private and Government Concerns

Designation : Assistant Project Manager

Period : May 2004-August 2007

## Responsibilities

- Actively responsible for exploring various activities such as planning, purchase of material, site visits
- Identified quality civil workers and allocated the workload to them.

- Monitored the quality of work in construction and erections
- Administrated all levels of project works.
- Responsible for the generation and maintenance of reports and relevant letters according to the senior direction
- Maintained good work relationships with subcontractors, Engineers & suppliers.

#### **T- Scale Constructions & Interiors**

# A Construction & Interior concern doing all types of civil construction works and interior works.

Designation : Project Coordinator

Period : January 2000 to March 2004

## Responsibilities

Implemented Interior design for IT offices like Elevation glassworks and false ceiling works.

- Developed interior design concept as per consumer need with architect advice.
- Monitored and executed all types of civil and Interior works with quality which includes foundation works, basement works, RC works, infrastructure works.
- Maintained good working relationship with Subcontractors, engineers & Suppliers.

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION**

Educational Qualification : MBA, and Project Management Professional (PMP)

Technical Qualification : Diploma in Civil Engineering

Computer Skills : AutoCAD, MS Project

Technical Experience : 20+ years [ Project Management]

# PERSONAL DETAILS

Martial Status : Married

Date of Birth : 08/05/1976

Languages Known : English and Tamil

Address for : A1, A block, Parru Apartment, East Agraharam Street,

Communication Singanallur, Coimbatore-641005

# **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the above-furnished details are true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Coimbatore Yours faithfully,

Date:

Karthikeyan.M